Rayyan Waseem

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan | 92-323-0717608 | mail | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Versatile developer with a Bachelor's in Computer Science, over a year of experience in Full Stack technologies. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail. Efficient in collaborating and communicating new ideas and opinions.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Beyond Commit: Git, GitHub & Copilot Challenge | Microsoft

January 2024

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, Java, Python, SQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, DHTML, JSON, Solidity

Frameworks: React, Node.js, ExpressJS, Bootstrap, Hardhat

DevOps and API Tools: Git, Postman, AWS

Cloud and Security Tools: Microsoft Server, Linux (Configuring and Managing) **Others**: Agile (Scrum/Kanban), Design Patterns, Debugging, Root Cause Analysis

EXPERIENCE

Back-end Developer | Eleciam LLC

February 2024 - September 2024

- Lead the development and maintenance of robust, scalable backend systems, ensuring high performance and reliability.
- Designed and implemented cutting-edge APIs to facilitate seamless communication between frontend and backend systems.
- Continuously refactored and improved the existing codebase to enhance maintainability, readability, and scalability.

System Administration Internee | PARCO Oil Refinery

July 2023 - August 2023

- Reduced system installation times by implementing ISOs with preinstalled software saving 100+ hours.
- Wrote a report to implement Application Group policy to 1000+ workstations in the company network.
- Studied how large scale security systems are maintained and implemented.

Web3 Developer | Freelance

January 2023 - June 2024

- Rigorous testing of smart contracts to ensure all edge cases are ironed out and DAO works smoothly
- Employed APIs of premium tools like MetaMask to reduce deployment cost by 50%
- Increased Organic CTR by adapting a no KYC policy ensuring security and anonymity.

App Developer | Freelance

June 2021 - December 2022

- Faster development times by creating singletons to handle repetitive tasks which decreased debugging time by 40%
- Decreased load times by 13% by adapting clean coding practices.
- Adapting hardware rendering for more smooth interacting in apps.

Web Developer | Freelance

January 2020 - May 2021

- Development of Websites and Web Apps using industry leading Frameworks.
- Implemented pleasing UI/UX that enhances user engagement

EDUCATION

NFC IET Multan
Karam-Dad Qureshi High School
PARCO High School

BS in Computer Science | GPA : 3.42
Pre-Engineering | A+
September 2018 - August 2020
September 2018 - August 2020
September 2016 - August 2018

PROJECTS

BCrypty | React+ViteJS, Web3.JS, MetaMask, Harhat, Blockchain

September 2023

- Developed a Web App to send and receive cryptocurrency all over the world.
- Use of MetaMask API to connect to our web app and contract deployment using Hardhat
- Documentation of the entire Project development process.

Deviddy Back-end | JavaScript, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, PostmarkJS, Postman, Git

February 2024

- Development of backend for a social media application for consuming short form content.
- Designed Scalable backend and robust APIs for fast access.
- Rigorous testing of API endpoints using Postman
- Use of Bearer Token Authentication and email verification
- Implemented a custom workflow using Git and GitHub to deploy application to online server

REFERENCES

Available upon request